Well, let's get started in
today's class.  Hey, let's start according to the
schedule that you already know is
planned.  Okay, wait a minute and let me put
the calendar on the screen here.  Well,
the classes, as you can see,
are grouped on Mondays and Thursdays.
Come on, today I'm going to say mine, eh, then there
are Alicia's and Pilar's
with IP, okay?  But I'm talking
specifically about mine.  So,
well, let's get started.  Today
is Thursday, the 11th, okay?  Let's
start with markup languages.  It's
two o'clock.  And first of all, what I'm going to
tell you is that all the code I'm going
to do can be found at
jithhab.com/jocarsa.
Let's see it.  Bardam2526.
Okay, everything I'm going to do you'll
find here.  Now then I remove this.
So let's start with first,
let's start with what we're doing today now in
markup languages.  Let's
start with markup languages ​​now.  And in
markup languages, the first thing
we find is a teaching unit that
tells us how to recognize the
characteristics of
markup languages.
So let's see first what the
classification is.  Let's see what
types of markup languages ​​we can
find and let's start to see
what markup languages ​​are useful for.
So to do this, first of all, let's
see, let's create a series of
contents.  I'm going to go and start up a
code editor.   I'm
going to open the chat, wait, I don't know
if you're telling me something in the chat.
Okay, I'll leave the chat open.
Good.  And from here, and from
here I'm going to go to DD, to
Dam, I'm going to go to first, I'm going to go
to markup languages, I'm going to go to
recognition of the characteristics of
markup languages, in
classification I'm going to go to exercises and
this is where I'm going to work.  That is to
say, I am going to use this structure at all times
with the objective that you
always know where I am, you always
know what course I am in, what
subject I am in, what
teaching unit I am in and what
teaching subunit I am in.  In this case, to
start guiding you, you will see that
the entire course will be like this.  We are in the
professional module subject,
markup languages, unit, recognition of the
characteristics of
markup languages, subunit classification.
Within each unit and subunit, you will
find an
initial summary, then a series of
exercises, then exercises that
I do, and then some evaluation criteria,
that is, some exercises that I will
give you over time.  Okay?
Well, let's start by saying that the
most well-known markup language
that exists is HTML.  So I'm going to create
a file 001 html.html.
And I'm going to write this markup language for now
, okay? Quickly.  And
now, in the use of
markup languages ​​in web environments, we
will gradually learn
the HTML language step by step.  For now
I want to put a demonstration.  Doc type
HTML.  HTML,
I have a head, I have a body
and I'm just going to put P here inside.
This is a web page and that's it.
So the most
well-known markup language we have, Hello, Sandro, very
good.  And I see Jonathan around too
.  The most well-known markup language we
have is HTML.
With this language we can create
web pages, but we
can also create documents.  These
are the two three things that markup
languages ​​are most commonly used for
, okay?  to create documents
and to create interfaces or websites.  Uh,
yeah, I'm recording.
You scared me so much I'm recording.  I have
this program here next to it.  The thing is, you
might not see the pilot
up here of recording with this with Zoom.
Okay, but don't worry because I'm not recording
with Zoom, but with another
program that I have on the
other screen right now, which is why you can't see it.
Okay, but don't worry, I don't forget to
record, or maybe one day I'll forget to
record. I mean, of course, exactly,
I record with OBS, but it wouldn't hurt if you
reminded me.
Okay, so as I was saying, as I
was saying, um, this is, okay, a first
markup language.  At this point
in the class, you'll start
asking, okay, what program are you
opening?  What program are you
working with?  What program are you
editing with?  Okay, I use a program that
is specifically for Linux called
Heit, which is nothing more than a
text editor.  You can work with whatever
program you want.  In fact, in
upcoming classes we'll talk about
development environments and what types
of development environments exist, but
you can work with any program
you want.  It is very common for you to use a
very nice and attractive program
called Visual Studio from Microsoft.
No problem, okay?  You can
use it if you want.  So, for
now I'm using a text editor,
as simple as possible,
as easy as possible to use.  Just a
moment, I'll take advantage and go to
assistants.  Here participants.   I
don't know what's wrong with Zoom,
but
okay.  Well, I don't know.  Okay,
so another markup language that we
're going to see very frequently is
the XML language.  So, I come
here, while the HTML language,
now we will see features and areas
of application, okay?  But hey, let's
talk in this case about, look, you know?
Well, I'll see about that now.
Characteristics and areas of application.
I'm going to copy this
and say new file 001 create
websites with html punhtml
in application scopes, okay?  One
area of ​​application, we will now talk
more about classification here, is creating
languages ​​with HTML.  As I was saying, another
markup language is creating documents
with XML, a markup language called
XML.
So from here, let's see for a
moment.  I'll take this out here,
okay?  I take this out here, I take this out
here.
Okay,
and as I was saying, another
markup language, I'm going to take
this header, it's the XML language.
Within the XML language, for
example, I can create custom tags
and say, I want to create a person.  And from
this person we are going to create personal data
and then experience or training.
And then training.
In personal data I'm going to put, for
example, a label called name,
another label called surname
and for example within name I'm going to
put José Vicente and within surname
I'm going to put Carratalá Sánchez.
Okay, let's see what happens if we put
this on a website.  For this I'm going to go to
the folder.
Where are you?  The folder is missing.
I'm going to go to the folder.
I'm going to SMR.  SMR.  No, I'm going to
DAM.  It's up here.
Dam. I'm going to go to markup languages ​​first
.  I'm going to e here.
No, not here.  I'm going here.  Subunit two,
exercises, okay?  And for example, I throw
this HTML file into Chrome or Chromium
or whatever.  Okay, just a moment to
access
here
, because this is a
web page.  This is the result of the code
we wrote earlier, which was
this code here.  And now, what
if what I want instead
is?
What I want
here is to load the
XML file.  Well the XML file is this one
here.  If you notice, the web browser
shouldn't necessarily show me an
XML file,
but in this case it's
previewing it.
So
what is HTML used for?
To create websites.  What is the
XML language used for?  To create documents.
There's another markup language, okay?
We are putting features.
what each one is used for, areas of
application and a little bit about what shape they have.
You see that in markup languages ​​there are
open tags and
closed tags in a large number of
them.  Don't have.  Oh, okay.  Okay.  Now
the next question is, what other
markup languages ​​are there?  These two are the
main ones, but there are more.  Or there's
another markup programming language,
sorry, called markdown.
to create dot html pun documents,
sorry, the extension of the
markdown type document is MD.  So now I
open this document and I say,
let's see a moment, give me a second, what
the heck is this call?  Let's see,
I'm in class.  Tell me.
Okay, but tell me.
If I can.  Yes, yes,
yes, yes,
yes.  Correct.  We'll talk about it now, but
yes.
Okay.
No problem.
Okay,
okay now, nothing, excuse me, I'm here now.
So, uh, Marku is
also for creating documents and you'll say,
if Markdown is a language for creating
documents and XML is for creating
documents, which one do I take?  Well, there's no
need to choose.  Okay?  I teach you
markup languages ​​and from there
you will use each one for whatever
interests you.  In the long run you will
all use them, okay?  In the long term, as your
needs arise,
you will use one language or another.
Well, this is a header.
Level one header.
This is a level two header.
This is plain text.
This is a list item
and so is this.
This is a vertical separator
and this
is a code block.  It's a
quick demo, okay?  It's a
quick test to show you that
markup languages ​​don't hurt,
okay?  Simply because they allow us to
save information.
You'll see that it seems like a rather
unattractive language, but nevertheless, if I
now open that
Markdown file to create documents, you'll see
that in this case I'm seeing it because
I have a browser plugin that is
capable of interpreting Markdown, right?
But you'll see that this is a
level one heading, this is a level
two heading, this is plain text, but this
is a list item and this is also a list item
and this is a code block.
Okay?  So
what conclusions can we draw
from these three languages ​​we've
seen so far?  Well, the
conclusions we draw are that there are
different markup languages.  Let's go,
I'm going to put here new file 001
conclusions that we can draw
point MD.
And so markup languages
contain
information.
Unlike
programming languages, which
process data, process
things, markup languages ​​contain
information.  Well, from there, from
there, there are different
languages.
Each of them has its own
syntax rules.  can have Yes, yes, I know, I
know, I know, Jonathan.  The reason
this file is numbered 09 is
because I'm now going to want to
create the 004 CSS file next, but I don't want
the conclusion to be left and
then the CSS, but I've put 009
to force it to be left last.
Yes, I haven't told you, but it's
okay.  On other occasions, the clamp is looked at
with the issue of the number, but
precisely in this case today it is not.  Okay,
so each one has some
syntax rules, they're not very complex
and then keep in mind that, uh,
in the end,
given that markup languages ​​are
for documents, in computer science,
computer information is not about processing,
computer science is about documents, about
information, okay?  It's normal, it's common
for information to be stored in
documents,
okay?  And so,
markup languages,
markup languages
help us do two things: one,
saving
documents,
and two, creating websites and creating
web interfaces.
And this is basically what we're going
to do in this subject, okay?  This
is what we are going to do.  We're going to be
learning different languages, not
a lot, but yes, of course,
obviously the most important ones.
And
as I was saying, as I was saying, Jonathan,
uh, I'm leaving this to put
here 004. There is a language called CSS.
CSS allows us to add style to HTML.
I'm going to call it dot html.  And then I'm going
to create a doctepe HTML HTML
HTML
head
body and body document.  And then I say P. This is
a
website.
Okay, and here inside the head I'm going to create
a style tag
and inside the style tag I'm going to
put a different language than those I
've talked to you about so far,
which is called CSS.  The CSS language works
in conjunction with HTML to perform
sterilization.  So, in this case,
for example, later on you will see that
we have in the
Where are you?  Here in the use of
markup languages ​​in web environments,
we have CSS style sheets, right?
That's why I say it looks like I'm
running, but I'm not.  So, I'm
now giving you an introduction to
what each programming language is for.  And do
n't worry, when the time comes, we'll
start to go into
each of the languages ​​and we'll go
little by little in each language and all that,
okay?  So relax about that.  Okay,
I'm going, as I was saying, to the P and here in
the P I say that the color is red, the color
of that text is red, so I'll
come back here later, right?  Then I come over
here,
reload, go to CSS and check that it's
true that the text is no longer
black, but red, right?
So the idea with the CSS language,
wait a minute, wait a minute.
Okay,
okay.  The idea with CSS is to have a language
that can support us, right?, and that
can stylize us and that
will ultimately be very important for
web pages to have a certain
structure.  Okay, from here, from
here, uh, let's see, I want to
see two more languages, okay?  I want to see
two more markup languages.  One of
them is not really a language, one
of them is the JSON 005
JSON format for saving puns documents,
right?  The JSON format is technically
JavaScript and is a subformat for
storing objects.  What happens is that the
objects end up being
really similar to the
documents, right?  So, for
example, what I'm going to do here is
create a key and inside the
key I'm going to put the name, colon José
Vicente, comma,
last name, colon Carratalá Sánchez,
comma, phone number or email
is info@jocarsa.
com.  Okay, and this is a jon.
As you will see, in the end, if we want it, it
saves the same information as
an XML file.  The difference is that an
XML file has a specific syntax, it
has opening tags and
closing tags, while
a JSON file has a
different syntax, which in this case comes from
JavaScript.  Which one is better between the
two?  Neither one is better than the other,
okay?  We will use each one in one
scenario or another, but ultimately
when I want to save documents, I
can use one or I can use
another.  Now, now,
yes, in this case what I'm going to do,
what I want to do in this case is to
focus on one thing, which is
structuring.   That
is, I, for example, here before in
XML, we are going to create another document, 006
eh J are nested.  For example, I can
come here and say, look, this is
personal data,
and then I put an object here, and
then inside an object I have another one.   I
can nest and then I can put
formation here and then I create another
object and I put formation one and uh
description
comma formation two and description.
Okay, and so on with each piece of
information I need to put in.
Sure, what's going on?  Well, then, for
example, I go into Mark and Markdown doesn't
have that style.  Markdown is not for
that, it is not for storing
nested information.  Markdown is for saving a
document
that has a very
presentation-type format,
let's call it that, Word-like, okay?
So, wait a minute, where are you?
Smartdown, here.  Type this.  So,
when I want a markup language to
present a Word-like document, I'll
use Mark; when I want a
markup language to store
complex information, I'll use JSON or XML.
So conclusions we can
draw.
For example, Markdown is
useful
for Word-type documents.
And uh, for example, XML and JSON are useful
for complex and nested documents.
Okay, we're going to take it easy
over the weeks, over the
course, to see what each document format is for
and in what scenarios you can use it.
Yes, Sandro, look, nested
basically means that one thing
is inside another.  In this case, there is
a category called personal data, and
within this category there are elements
such as, for example, name,
surname, or email.  This thing about
things being inside each other is what is
called nesting in programming and computer science, right?  And then there's
another language I want to see.  There are
many, okay?  That is, I am showing
a small
sample of all of them.  There is another
language
called 007 SVG for creating graphics.   It
is a small language
that we use to create graphics,
especially two-dimensional ones.
Okay?  So, just a moment, I'm going to
look for a little example.
SVG can be made very complex.
I'm looking for the simplest SVG example
I can get my hands on.  Now, in a
moment I'll take a 30-second micro-pause
to plug in the charger, as you
can see I'm taking too long.  Let's see.
No, just a moment.  Not now.
Let's see, let's take the label,
the main label.  I'm going to take advantage of this
to drink.
We're seeing a lot
of formats at the moment.  You will say, "
My goodness."  Of course, the subject is
called markup languages, and
evidently, there
will be several markup languages.
Okay, I'm going to take this one.
I'll take this example.  So in
an SVG file, we
first create the SVG tag.  Let's
say WI 512,
height 512.
And I'm going to create in this case, for
example, a circle.  Let's
start with a circle.  Center X at 256,
center Y at 256
and that would give you radius 100 and color red.
All of these are properties and attributes.
Now I will tell you about this next.
If you want to see it simpler, I'll
do it like this.  I'm going to do it like this.  I'm going to do it
like this.
And I'm going to do the same thing in the circle
.  And so you will understand that all of these
are nothing more than attributes of a single
label.  Okay, so what happens when
I run this?  Well, what happens
when I run this is that I have, look,
the flag of Japan without having wanted it,
uh, I have a white canvas and in the
middle of the canvas I have a
red circle, okay?  So,
while HTML, for example, is a
markup language that allows us to create websites, SVG
is a markup language that allows us to
create drawings.  And obviously, when
I want to create a
website
that has drawings, I'll use
HTML and I'll use SVG.  HTML for the web and
SVG for drawings, okay?  So this is
kind of the point, to show you that there are
different markup languages.  Now
we will go into more detail on each of
them, and each one will serve us for
different purposes.
In this subject, I want to take
advantage of today to begin
teaching you a markup language that is
the simplest you can imagine.   the
simplest markup language we
can imagine today.  I don't
know.  Hey, okay, Sandro, right?  SVG
is originally designed to work in
2D.  However, don't worry because in
JavaScript, which is a
programming language that we will see
shortly, there is a part called web
GL, which does allow us to
work in 3D and represent
3D information.  So, no SVG, but don't worry,
we will see how to represent
3D spaces, especially because I am
firmly convinced that the future
of the web is 3D.  I'll tell you more
about this later.  I don't
want to bore you with too much detail today on the
subject of 3D, but I think 3D is going to
be much more important
on the web than it has been in recent decades.
Well, as I was saying, I want to teach you
the Markdown language.  Let's see, delete it
here.  Okay, so I'm going to
basically teach you, basically we're going to
look at
the Markdown language.  The
Markdown language is very important for things
like, for example,
artificial intelligence, no less.  and GitHub,
okay?  And publish your code on
GitHub.  Therefore, you have to learn
the Markdown language, but if it's the
first one I'm going to teach you, it's
precisely because it's the simplest.
So don't worry, in the half hour
we have left you'll leave here
knowing Mark.  Okay, so next
we're going to create a new file and we're going to
start turning on markdown.  These are
headings.
MD point.   I
come here and say, this is a
level one heading.
This is a
level 2, 3,
four and five heading.
This is level two, three,
four,
five
and six.  This is the maximum.
Two,
3, 4, 5 and six.
We're going to come back this way.
Paren directory.  Paren directory.
Classification.
Exercises.  Headings.  Okay?  And as you
can see, it is represented in the form of
headers, a bit like Word,
let's say.
Jonathan is literally the same
as HTML.  In fact, with this
renderer that I have for
Markdown format, in fact, if I inspect the
browser, you'll see that it's putting it
as an H1, literally.  Okay?
So
the important concept, the
important concept is
level one heading.  That concept is
multilingual, right?  The thing is
, how is the
level one header implemented in each
programming language?  Well in HTML it is implemented
as H1 and here it is implemented as a
hash mark, okay?  But that is what
the concept is, what matters.  Okay, so
let's get to work on more
Mark 002 stuff. Let's talk about paragraphs
and breaks.
paragraphs
and line breaks pund.
So this is a
paragraph content, but be
careful because this is not another
paragraph.
So if I now run this
file, we
can see that it doesn't skip
paragraphs.  To jump to a new paragraph, you
have to press enter twice.
So,
Sandro, indeed, okay, I'm going to take
a short break to talk about what you
just said.  So,
HTML is a language created in 1991.
The person who created HTML, I'll
tell you later, is called Tim Bernerslee. He created
HTML with the intention of making it
as simple as possible, but over
the years, well, people,
especially people who are just starting to
learn it, complain that it's
difficult to learn.  I don't think so.  In
Hello, tell me.  Oh, okay.  Back in 2001 2002
the Mark language came out.  And what
the language tried to do was simplify
HTML even further.  Therefore, what you are
seeing is actually correct.
Okay, Mark's aesthetic is simpler.
I can't
think of anything simpler than Markdown right now, and
that's why I like Mark.  Throughout the
course you will realize that I am
a person who values
simplicity and straightforwardness above all else.  Okay?
Good.  So from here, from
here we have eh of Okay, but what
if I want to represent two paragraphs,
okay?  This is
another paragraph,
okay?  two line breaks.  This is another
paragraph, but what if I want to put two
different lines, well, this is a
line
point space space
and then I say, this is another line.
created two spaces
and in this way you will see how now with
a double space it is a little trick of maown
if you want it for whatever you can go
down you can force a carriage return
we are going to talk next about the
emphasis 003 emphasis and to emphasize
we can work on the one hand with the
text in italics
And this represents the text as
italic text.  Then, below
we have the bold text.
And this is text.  Hey, watch out, what's going on
here?
Sorry, bold text has to be
together.  And finally,
three asterisks.  is bold and italics
and three asterisks.  By the way, what
can I say? Luckily, this first
class is about markup language.
All the activities you're going to
hand in during this course will be
handed in in Markup language.  So do
n't worry, in the end, and I would say
even soon, you'll be
working in Mark language.
You're seeing that it couldn't possibly be
simpler.  Look, the time has
come, my battery is low,
so I'm going to activate the charger, so
I'm going to take this 30-
second micropause and let's see,
let's see
here.
Oh,
okay.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.  Wait a
minute, I'm fighting with the cable.
Okay.  And here.
Very good.  Come on, here we are.  Perfect.
Okay, let's continue.  We have bold
and italics.  Let's uh create lists.
Okay, to create lists we have on the one
hand 004
unordered lists
and in the unordered lists I have this
is an element,
this is another element
and this is one more element.
If I want to make ordered lists, 005,
ordered lists, I have to put
the number first and then a period.  One,
two, 3, okay?  And this is one
more element.  If I load the lists,
this is an item
and this is a numbered item.
To put hyperlinks, the great strength
of HTML.  In HTML, HT is hypertext
, right?  languages, sorry,
oh, hyperlinks in Marki
hyperlinks
are through this syntax, which is eh
link to the Jocarsa website.
And now here inside, in parentheses,
https 2/johsa.com.
If we represent this, we can
see how I have a hyperlink and when I
click on the hyperlink I go to the
Jucarsa website, which is mine.
From here we will also upload
images.  We can load 007
images.
So in images the syntax is very
similar,
right?  This is Jocarza's logo.
And then I put the image.
Instead of putting my logo which is
white on the website, I'm going to put this
image.  Copy image address
and I'm going to put an image that is a
logo for one of the programs I
develop.  Okay?  So we do it like
this.
We do it like this, okay?  and we have that
we can embed an image inside
of Markow.  Okay?
Okay, let's talk about dating.
Citations are when you quote content from
another author, 008 citations.
And we're going to put greater than this is a
quote
and this is a nested quote.  I save,
reload
and you'll see that the appointments look like this
, okay?  It's like when you put
text that isn't yours, but actually belongs to someone
else.
In markdown, putting code is easy,
right?  If I want to add a block of
code, which in our case is going to be very
frequent, I can do it as
inline code.
So I say,
in HTML there
is the tag and I put Accent Vert
HTML Accent Vert and it serves to declare
the document.  What the program does is
mark that label in a
special way that makes it clear that it is an
instruction from a
programming language.  And if you want to create a
code block
010 code block.
Next
we're going to look at a block in Python
and then I put accent, accent, accent,
accent, accent, accent and I say print
hello world in Python.
And if I now run it, you'll see that
instead of creating a small inline block of code
, what happens is that
a full-width block of code is created,
right?  Which, I insist, is
great for us programmers.
Finally, lastly, almost last, I'm going
to comment on the tables.  tables, not
separators.
Separators.
This is a text.  Guxo.
Gux
more.
So I reload,
go to separators and see how I have the
text, the separator, the text and the
separator.  Okay?  And now, now,
finally, we're going to talk about tables.
Making tables in Mark
of the world, especially compared to
HTML.  And we'll talk about HTML because 012
tables,
well I come here and say
vertical pipe.  The vertical pipe is done with
altgr and the number one.  And I say eh,
column
one
pipe, column two.
And now
I put
a set of scripts.  It's very 80s-like
, it's super cool, but now you'll see
that it's transformed, okay?  To a
truth table.  This is fact one.   I
put it there.
And here, for example, I could put
data two.
And okay and I give three
and four and
five and six.  And when I render that
table
what I see is this.  Oh, sorry, careful.
Oh, yeah, sure.  This is not necessary
because it is the column separator, that
is, the header separator.  Now
yes, okay?  And you see that it renders it to me
as a table.  And now he worries,
Jonathan, for what we will see in due
time regarding the subject of tables, he
worries about creating for me the table,
the T head, the T body,
the TR, the TD, everything
else, okay?  So, as I say,
Markown is, I insist, Markown is our
best friend in the sense that with very
little effort on our part we can
make draws.  Indeed, in HTML it is
a pain in the ass.  I don't know who
invented them, but they showed off, but yeah,
okay.  Markdown is the simplest language you
can learn when
you need to create a document, and you're
going to need it because you'll
be submitting your assignments to me in Markdown format, or
when the software you
develop needs to create a
document.
This is the way to do it, okay?  This is
one of the ways, one of the formats
available in
programming languages, to
correctly save information.
What doesn't Markdown have?  Well,
let's see, let's see.   No
no.  Let's see.  Sure, you say, it's the
format that Linux pages use
when someone wants to search for
commands, right?
What are Linux pages?  I don't know
if you're referring to the
official documentation.  Yeah, but what I want to tell you
is that there are a ton of Linux pages
on the internet and therefore there will be some
that do and others that don't.  Now, what I'm
going to tell you is that one of the
things we usually do in computing
is document.  That is, when you make
software, you have to create an
instruction document so that
people know how to use your
program.  Well, one of the
requirements, one of the most
common formats for documenting is precisely
the web.  A boy has come in, but
that boy will come here, won't he?  Wait,
a boy has come in, but I don't know if he's coming
with me.  Okay,
then that's it.  Nothing, basically I'm
telling you that the Markdown format, as
I say, is a format that we're going to use
at a given time for everything.  Okay?
Now, to finish up these
10 minutes, let's see,
these 10 minutes that we have from Mark,
what we're going to do next is
come up with a little practical exercise,
okay?  Something that can be useful to us.  Let's
see for a moment.  I'm thinking
about making a resume, but we
won't make the resume at Mark.   We will
write the resume in other
technologies, such as
XML or JSON.
Hm.  M. No, let's see
something that,
well, for example,
well, look, I don't know, documentation of a
program,
okay?  013
program documentation.
So, I come here and say, uh, the
name of the program, I mean, it's a
program called jocarsa.til.
Okay, so let's see, just a moment.
No, no, no, no, no.  Ah, okay, very good,
very good.  No, I'll tell you, I'll tell you.
Let's see.
Markdown is a language that requires
some kind of interpreter
or some kind of renderer to
display its content.  The
same thing really happens with HTML.  HTML is a markup language
, but HTML requires a
web browser to convert the HTML into something
content.  So what happens?  There are
different types of viewers for viewing
documents, eh, for viewing
Markdown documents, but in this specific case,
what I have is a
browser extension, a Chrome extension that
is for viewing Markdown files.  So
what happens?  Well, what happens is that, of
course, since I'm ultimately viewing
Mark through a web browser, the
web browser, the add-on,
is transforming it into HTML language.  But I do
n't want this to be understood as
meaning that all Markup will always be
converted to HTML because that's not the case.
This is only happening in this case, in
this particular viewer because I'm
using web technologies, right?
So that's why, okay?  But
throughout the course we will look at other
Markdown viewers and you will see that they do not
necessarily have to convert.
So, for example, I'm going to put an
introduction here and then I'll put
server requirements here and then I'll
put an example of using the
program here.
And then I say, for example,
Jocar Satil is an application that
can be used to create
interactive business applications.
allows us to
create applications,
create control panels,
control our data.
Server requirements to install
this application we
must one,
not necessarily, not necessarily, I
can recommend it to you, okay?  But
just open Google and put
Markdown Bware, okay?  Mark Viewer and
from there use whichever you want.
So to install this application we
must, uh, one, have a server,
two, use PHP,
uh, three, use MySQL
and then, for example, here an example
of how to use the program.  Here's
an example
of how to use it, okay?  And then pluo, pluco,
sample code in markdown and that's it.
Okay, so I save this little
file.  Next I come over
here
and I have this, okay?  I have a
document that has headings, that has
unordered lists, that has
ordered lists, that has a code block
and whatever we want, okay?  So,
Sony 53. Now, we'll
jump into the next subject,
which is, I don't remember, I think it's
programming, so
for today we've
actually done programming and then
databases.  Phenomenal.  Okay?  Hey, for today
we've done a first introduction
to markup languages.  We'll continue
on Monday, going deeper, and, well,
you know that over the next few
days, I'll comment on it later in the
afternoon, and I'll also comment on it by
email, so, I'll send it to you through
the forms you filled out, okay?
Confirm that you've filled out the
survey I sent you a couple of days ago
regarding hobbies and all that,
and I'll send you personalized ones for you to
do regarding the two
subunits we saw today.  I
mean, I mean,
if any of you guys tell me,
okay?  If any of you tell me,
for example,
compress,
okay?  Okay.
For example, I come here,
now I open GPT chat here
and I say, where are you?
Hello.
created.
Oysters!  Now and here.
Okay, I'll take an artificial intelligence
and say, based on this characterization
of markup languages, give an example or
give an exercise
for the students regarding
feature films
.  If any of you have
told me that you like feature films
,
with which,
with which exercise,
then create an XML document where you
represent the title of the film, the
year of release, the director and if
someone, Of course, this is the result,
okay?  I don't want him to take this out, okay?
But
hey, if someone tells me movies,
well, the exercise will be about movies.  If
someone says football, then the exercise
will say about football, okay?  I will give each of you
an exercise that I have thought of according to
the form that you have already filled out.  Okay?
Well, let's take a
5-minute break.  M.